{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The technique first described to determine the incipient spoilage in meat was", "opta": "homogenate extract volume (HEV)", "optb": "agar Plate Count (APC)", "optc": "extract Release Volume (ERV)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is responsible for a musty or earthy flavor?", "opta": "Actinomycetes", "optb": "Flavobacterium", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Pseudomonas syncyanea", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Molds causing spoilage of eggs include species of", "opta": "Cladosporium", "optb": "Mucor", "optc": "Thamnidium", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vacuum packaged meats are spoiled by", "opta": "B. thermosphacta", "optb": "Lactobacilli", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "More spoilage of eggs is caused by", "opta": "bacteria than molds", "optb": "molds than bacteria", "optc": "synergistically", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The growth of Streptomyces on straw or elsewhere near the egg may produce", "opta": "musty or earthy flavors", "optb": "hay odour", "optc": "fishy flavor", "optd": "cabbage-water flavor", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Unopened, sliced bacon, packaged in material somewhat highly resistant to oxygen permeability, is spoiled mostly by", "opta": "Lactobacilli", "optb": "Micrococci", "optc": "fecal Streptococci", "optd": "molds", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pink rots in eggs is caused by the strains of", "opta": "Pseudomonas", "optb": "Pseudomonas fluorescens", "optc": "species of Micrococcus or Bacillus", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Beef hams are made spongy by species of", "opta": "Rhodotorula", "optb": "Bacillus", "optc": "Pseudomonas", "optd": "red Bacillus", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The red color of meat, called its bloom, may be changed to shades of green, brown or grey as a result of production of oxidizing compounds by bacteria. Which of the following species are reported to cause the greening of sausage?", "opta": "Lactobacillus", "optb": "Leuconostoc", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Pseudomonas", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Yellow discolorations in meat are caused by bacteria with yellow pigments, usually species of", "opta": "Micrococcus", "optb": "Flavobacterium", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Pseudomonas syncyanea", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following (s) is/are responsible for the green patches on the surface of meats under aerobic conditions?", "opta": "P. expansum", "optb": "P. asperulum", "optc": "P. oxalicum", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following microorganisms grow in beef at a temperature of 15\u00b0C and above?", "opta": "Micrococci", "optb": "Pseudomonas", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Lactobacillus", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Green rots in eggs is chiefly caused by", "opta": "Pseudomonas fluorescens", "optb": "Micrococcus or Bacillus species", "optc": "Molds or yeasts", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Black rots in eggs is most commonly caused by", "opta": "species of Proteus", "optb": "species of Micrococcus or Bacillus", "optc": "molds or yeasts", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In storage atmospheres of high humidity variety of molds may cause", "opta": "superficial fungal spoilage", "optb": "bacterial spoilage", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following microorganism spoil poultry in polyethylene bags?", "opta": "Pseudomonas-achromobacter", "optb": "Alcaligenes", "optc": "hetero-fermentative species", "optd": "catalase negative bacteria", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Black spot in meat are produced mainly by", "opta": "Cladosporium", "optb": "Thamnidium", "optc": "Mucor", "optd": "Rhizopus", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the cause(s) has/have been suggested for the chill rings in sausage?", "opta": "Oxidation", "optb": "Production of organic acids or reducing substances by bacteria", "optc": "Excessive water", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lactic acid bacteria in meats may be responsible for", "opta": "slime formation at the surface or within especially in presence of sucrose", "optb": "production of green discoloration", "optc": "souring", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Colorless rots in eggs is caused by", "opta": "Pseudomonas alcaligenes", "optb": "Pseudomonas fluorescens", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The greening of sausage may appear as a green ring not far from the casing, a green core, or a green surface. The cause of greening is the production of hydrogen peroxide by", "opta": "hetero-fermentative species", "optb": "catalase negative bacteria", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Iced, cut up poultry often develops a slime i.e. accompanied by an odor describe as tainted, acid, sour or dishraggy. This defect is chiefly by the species of", "opta": "Pseudomonas", "optb": "Alcaligenes", "optc": "hetero-fermentative species", "optd": "catalase negative bacteria", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is recommended for the improvement in flavor during ageing of beef under controlled conditions?", "opta": "Thamnidium", "optb": "Rhizopus", "optc": "T. elegans", "optd": "M. mucedo", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The spoilage of eggs by fungi goes through stages of mold growth that give the defects their names. Very early mold growth is termed", "opta": "pin-spot molding", "optb": "fungal rotting", "optc": "superficial fungal spoilage", "optd": "any of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "White spot in meat is formed due to presence of", "opta": "P. expansum", "optb": "Sporotrichum carnis", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "P. oxalicum", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}